# **SYED TALHA KHALID**

+ (92) 333-3948741 syedtalhakhalid@outlook.com

A-115 Block 18 Gulshan-e-Iqbal Karachi,Sindh

## Summary

Energetic System Consultant with 4+ years' experience in Software development, business intelligence analysis and technical support. I strongly wish to work for and grow with an organization that offers multicultural environment and growth opportunities so that, I can best utilize capability, boost my knowledge based skills, enthusiastically work & learn in co-operative environment.

# Work History

SYSTEM CONSULTANT - 11/2017 to Present
Millennium Systems and Consultants Pvt Ltd, Karachi

- Participate in complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) for proper analysis, development, testing, deployment and enhancement of the code for the c# windows applications development, ASP.Net development and Android Application Development.
- Play a key role in writing application logic and creating database structure.
- Analyze user interface and consulted with client. Followed up by testing (user interface, errors with all possible inputs, debugging, publishing) apps after project completion.
- Provide Technical Support to client.
- Worked well independently also lead team co-ordination.

#### Jr. Software Engineer - 01/2016 to 10/2017

Millennium Systems and Consultants Pvt Ltd, Karachi

- Tuned and improved software source code based upon new user requirements and technical guidelines.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Performed software testing to uncover bugs and troubleshoot.

Trainee Software Engineer - 11/2015 to 12/2015 Millennium Systems and Consultants Pvt Ltd, Karachi

### Education

#### 2017-08 - 2019-12

FAST National University of Computer and Emerging Science, Karachi MS in Software Project Management, Information Technology

#### 2011-01 - 2014-12

Sir Syed University of Engineering and Technology, Karachi BS in Computer Engineering, Information Technology

### Skills

- C#
- Microsoft SQL Server
- SAP Crystal Reports
- Windows\Web Services (WCF)
- Application Deployment
- RPGLF
- DB2
- Production Support
- Networking
- ASP.NET
- Technical Analysis

# **Projects**

#### 2020-06 - Present

Remote Banking Transaction System - Bank Al Jazira Development and Testing

#### Language / OS:

IBM ISeries, RPGLE, AS 400, ASP.NET, SQL Server, SAP crystal report

#### 2019-09 - Present

Remote Banking Transaction System - Implemented at Habib Bank Limited Development, Testing and Technical Support

#### Language / OS:

IBM ISeries, RPGLE, AS 400

#### 2018-11 - 2019-05

Mortgage Loan Application and Document Automation - Implemented at United Bank Limited (UK) Requirements elicitation, Development, Testing, Deployment and Technical Support

#### Language / OS:

Visual Studio 2012, SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise, ASP.NET (c#), SQL, Crystal Reports, DB2

#### 2018-05 - 2018-08

Online Tanker System - Implemented at Karachi Water & Sewerage Board (KWSB - Sindh Government) Requirements elicitation, Development, Deployment and Production support

#### Language / OS:

Visual Studio 2012, SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise, ASP.NET (c#), SQL, Crystal Reports

#### 2016-11 - 2017-03

MSCL Clinic - Implement at National Cardio Vascular and Disease (NICVD)

Development, Testing, Training and Production Support

#### Language / OS:

Visual Studio 2012, SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise, ASP.NET (c#), SQL, Crystal Reports

#### 2018-05 - 2018-08

Online Tanker System - Implemented at Karachi Water & Sewerage Board (KWSB - Sindh Government) Requirements elicitation, Development, Deployment and Production support

#### Language / OS:

Visual Studio 2012, SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise, ASP.NET (c#), SQL, Crystal Reports

#### 2016-11 - 2017-03

MSCL Clinic - Implement at National Cardio Vascular and Disease (NICVD) Development, Testing, Training and Production Support

#### Language / OS:

Visual Studio 2012, SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise, ASP.NET (c#), SQL, Crystal Reports

## Certifications

- Microsoft Certified Professional (2014)
- MCSA: Web Applications (2014)
- MCSD: App Builder
- Cloud Analytics Practitioner

### Interests

Travelling, Music, Watching Seasons

# Languages

English, Urdu